As you may have noticed, a few months ago,
I got the "PT" taken out of my
Instagram handle,
and I managed to get the name James Smith.
Because the truth is,
I'm just not a personal trainer anymore.
I did my last personal training session in
2017, and ever since then, I've
run an online business.
I'm not an influencer.
I don't do paid posts.
I am a digital marketer.
As I've said before,
I send traffic to websites.
But I'm about to make a couple more
business moves,
and I thought I might as well
explain them to you so you can see them
happening as they roll out.
Number one,
it's messy in here because I'm building a
studio upstairs.
I'll do the reveal of that
when it's ready.
Building a podcast studio because I'm
going to bring the podcast back.
But the amount of products
and services that I have for sale,
being my business
mentorship, my training app, Nutonic,
it's pretty stupid to not have the
podcast.
I've got nearly 15 million downloads,
and I kind of abandoned it because I
didn't really have a direction to go with
it. So that's coming back.
I'm going to be self-sponsoring the
podcast as well.
So although we're using an organization,
they're incredibly expensive.
Rather than getting ads in the pod,
we're just going to pay for everything
ourselves. And then rather than saying,
"This episode brought to you by
Nivea Face Cream", I'll just be like, "Oi,
dickheads, check out my mentorship.
Grab a can of Nutonic, you nonce." So
that project as a business move
is there to invest money into it to
inflate the value of the other
businesses. My mentorship
is coming up to a year and a half old,
and we've nearly hit $3 million, which
is nice.
I still think we're in the infancy of this
channel.
I would love to get this channel to
100,000, 200,000 subscribers, and I'm very
excited to know what
that would equate to in financial means.
Now,
there is a negative to the business
mentorship, which is the scalability of
it. The only lever I have,
because it's me that interacts with
everyone, I'm just
going to keep hiking the price up. And
if we had six people joining on 6,000 a
day,
that'd be a million a month. And
that would be really nice.
But I think I should tell you about the
next business play because it could
potentially be one of the biggest I've
ever made.
I started testosterone replacement therapy
about a year ago.
I'm now in better shape at 36 than I
was at 26.
And here's the crazy thing.
I live in the same house.
I train in the same gym.
I eat the same diet.
I have the same missus.
I have the same dog.
My inputs, all of it are the same,
but the outputs, more energy,
more drive, more motivation,
better libido, wild.
So you can imagine, three months in, I
was like, "Where's the business
opportunity in this?" I looked into
starting a clinic and the
legalities, the red tape,
the dealing with doctors, I was like,
"Nah, this is way
too much." So instead,
I started looking for an investment
opportunity.
Now, when you look at
that $3 million from the business
mentorship, I'm actually
using that to invest in different places.
Nutonic, we self-funded.
We never took on any investment in the
onset.
We had to put our own money into that.
Things like doing the podcast,
we're investing hundreds of thousands of
pounds into
that. So I was looking out
and trying to pry out the next investment
opportunity,
and I found a very good opportunity with a
UK-based
TRT organization.
I will be revealing who that is first via
email. So now, even in this video,
I'm going to say to check out the
businesses I
have.
I'm going to put them in the description.
I'm going to give you one for the business
mentorship, one for Nutonic, and one
called checkyourbloods.com.
First things first, I bought the domain.
My primary objective for this company
is going to be empowering
men with the information
and education that they need to go do a
blood test.
I don't get paid for the blood test.
I am not on any commission as far as that.
I'm now an investor in the business.
If the business does well, I do well,
and the business can only do well by
helping
men with low testosterone because
if they don't have low testosterone,
they can't
get access to the resources of the
business.
So from a funnel standpoint, education,
breaking down stigma, helping
men understand the basic elements of
everything to do with it,
then ultimately some
kind of squeeze page.
Bought the domain checkyourbloods.com,
that being my mission.
If you go to that right now, and
that will be a page where you put in your
information,
and you'll be the first to get emailed
about when we launch.
We only signed last week,
so we're still very much in the infancy of
this business
deal. So if you're a man over 30,
sign up to that.
Even if you don't suspect you have low
testosterone, it's probably a good idea to
get your levels checked so you know where
you are right now.
Because say in five years' time
or 10 years' time,
you might get to a position
where you do have symptoms of low
testosterone, and you can at least go,
"Five
years ago, I was here.
Now I'm here." There's never really a bad
outcome to getting
your bloods checked. And like I said,
I'm not on commission to tell you that.
I earn zero for every blood test that's
ordered.
So this will sit much like any of my other
businesses.
Education, empowerment,
use social media to take someone offline,
in this case via
the email.
I'm going to run an email marketing
automation to help men understand
all the things they need to about TRT.
And if there are any specific topics on
those videos that you want, comment them
down below,
and I will make them videos on the main
channel.
This is going to be another direction for
the main channel to go in.
And then via email marketing,
I would say to men, "This
is where you get your blood
test." It will be an at-home prick sample,
things like 30, 40
quid. And then from then, if they
are showing low levels of testosterone,
they
can then do a follow-up test,
then they can start treatment.
Everything in my career so far,
worked in corporate, loved fitness, quit.
My boss said, "Get into fitness.
You don't shut up about it." Did fitness
for a
long time. Thought could scale this,
scaled it, run a big successful business.
Running a big successful business,
thought, "Hmm,
I could monetize the consultancy
of helping other creators and coaches
and small businesses with this." Did that.
Started TRT.
I'm now going into the phase of helping
other people to get the
benefits I can. The beauty of this
is being a legit clinic, no
person will be able to give this business
money unless they want to and
they qualify.
So only men with low testosterone
that want testosterone replacement
as a service will be able to inflate my
shareholdings of that business.
There are no victims in this, which
is what makes it very exciting.
And then over the next few years,
I'm going to grow this business as large
as I
can,
and I want to make it the biggest in the
UK and hopefully the biggest in the
world.
And I want to partner with them to make
sure that the level of service, the
level of quality,
and the level of education
is up to par and to be
the leading out of all of them.
So then as a portfolio,
I want my fitness business
to continue to provide affordable coaching
to people that need it.
I want Nutonic to keep growing.
We've got some very exciting news about
that soon.
Maybe one day Coca-Cola come knocking.
Who knows?
Got the business mentorship,
which I'm going to keep driving demand
for, and
although it's not a scalable business,
I am just going to leverage the price up
and
down on that.
I'm going to bring back the main channel
in two realms, podcast for
general awareness to feed traffic to all
of those businesses, and then the
investment into the TRT service business
so that I can put out educational content
specific to my own journey
that I go through to empower other men to
make the same
decisions as me if they would like.
There's going to be crossovers.
A lot of dudes with high levels of
testosterone might want to train,
might use the
training app. Business mentorship events.
"Oh,
let's put a can of Nutonic on every
table." All the ecosystems work together.
Even right now, this
is a business channel,
and I've just used it for an UNAGI
plus four data-driven campaign to get
email addresses for
checkyourbloods.com.
I'm not going to lie to you.
From one story and one carousel,
we got 13,000
email addresses for this Check Your Bloods
project.
So when we start going full-blown campaign
education YouTube mode, the
potential for this is massive.
But similar to Nutonic,
being an investor in a
business means I don't get paid as we go
along.
I'm not an influencer saying swipe up
and getting my commission codes.
If the business exits in five years
and I've had a positive contribution to
the
direction of the business, that's
when your boy will get paid.
It's really exciting. I hope you guys
and maybe some of you ladies will be keen.
And for some of you like, "Oh,
come out a bit left field, James,
talking about
testosterone a lot." I've been banging the
drum for women and HRT and
menopause for years.
I just didn't realize that I
was going through manopause
in my late 30s.
So that's the next business move.
So sign up because I bought another car
today. Yep, bought another car.
You'll like it. That's it.
I'll show you in a bit. I got a problem.
I got a problem. I like cars. I like cars.
Thanks for watching. Bye-bye.